<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Index on juanramos.me</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/essays/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Index on juanramos.me</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/essays/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>On hopelessness</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/essays/hopelessness/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/essays/hopelessness/</guid>
      <description>Nowadays, I am starting to see commitment as the practice of letting go of the fantasy of utter certainty: that we&amp;rsquo;re ever going to find something that fully satisfies us, leaving no room for doubt, or regret.&#xA;I, too, am skeptical of rationality: I grew out of love with it during my early-twenties, when I started to realize how often it failed to make sense of reality and to fully capture whatever was really going on.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on Vividness</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/essays/vividness/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/essays/vividness/</guid>
      <description>Some time has passed by since I first started exploring Vajrayana buddhism, explicitly the flavour instilled by David Chapman&amp;rsquo;s Vividness.&#xA;As many others, I originally found it through his main site, Meaningness, which is still my main recommendation to anyone that find themselves on a confused place with regards to what&amp;rsquo;s the actual meaning of life, their purpose here, and everything else.&#xA;Back to Vajrayana, I find it to be a worldview that is exceptionally fruitful for those of us that get overwhelmed by the infinite amount of ways of being and acting that are preached upon on the internet.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ripping each other open</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/essays/ripping/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/essays/ripping/</guid>
      <description>This is a post I wrote a few months ago about the responsibility we have to be open to feedback. After reading Cate Hall&amp;rsquo;s piece about community-seekers vs truth-seekers, I can see how the whole purpose of this post is written from a community-seeker/connection-above-truth worldview, where it is assumed that conflict equals trouble.&#xA;If I were to write it again, I would focus on how being kind is actually different from being nice, and that real kindness requires saying stuff that might hurt the other (getting away as much as possible from being a jerk, of course), as the whole motif of being kind is caring about the others&amp;rsquo; wellbeing.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
